Jonathan Oliveira

Software Engineer

Passionate Software Engineer with 9+ years of experience. Working professionally as full-stack developer for 6+ years, focused on Java, Spring, AngularJS, HTML. Fast learner, software craftsmanship believer, problem-solver with can-do attitude, willing to deliver high quality software.



contato@jonathanoliveira.com

+1 (604) 260-6266

1844 West 7th Avenue, Vancouver, BC



http://www.jonathanoliveira.com



Work Experience (most recent)

03/2015 - Present Maringa, Brazil

Software Engineer

investor\$Tec @ investor\$Inc (personal project)

Real State Management Software for an international real estate advisory company.

- Displayed a really full stack role, from requirements gathering and project management to coding, deployment and server administration.
- Achieved fully continuous integration and continuous deploy environment with Bitbucket, Codeship and Heroku with virtually 100% app uptime.
- Managed many project challenges, such as cloud databases and large files and images uploads to the cloud (over 18k images).
- Automated several marketing processes such as brochure generation and images manipulations.
- Developed a REST API to integrate data to different websites.

Contact: Leandro Teles - teles@investorsinc.com.br

08/2014 - Present Maringa, Brazil

Software Engineer

Objective Solutions

http://www.objective.com.br/

Tasks/Achievements

- Participated in the development and maintenance of a large CRM & billing system with Java and internal frameworks.
- Worked with several satellite systems with different technologies such as Javascript, JSF, and HTML/CSS.
- Took the initiative to change technologies of a JSF project to AngularJS, meeting client's tight deadlines and budget requirements.
- Taught AngularJS and Spring to the other team members.
- Member of a development team with strong agile practices such as SCRUM, pair programming, code review, CI, XP and Kanban.

Contact: Joel Matsu - +55 44 9106-5675

06/2013 - 08/2014 Maringa, Brazil

Senior Java Developer

DB1 Global Software

http://www.db1.com.br

- Participated in outsourcing projects, with Java, defining architecture, programming, delegating tasks and managing follow-ups with other programmers.
- Automated several internal HR processes by making surveys, analyzing processes and developing a software to help HR operate more efficiently.
- Worked as a SCRUM Master of the development team and performed tasks of lesser complexity inherent in project management.
- Participated in an innovation project conducted internally with "My Loyalty Card".

Contact: Edoil Barros - +55 44 9125-1206

Education

01/2006 - 12/2014

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science State University of Maringa

Courses

- Compilers
- Artificial intelligence
- Programming languages
- Software engineering
- Algorithms
- Algorithms analysis

Skills & Competences

Mobile development (Ionic)	
lava/Spring	
AngularJS	
lavascript/HTML/CSS	
GQL	
Net	
JX/UI design	
Codeship/Heroku	
Sit/SVN	

Personal Projects

My Loyalty Card

 Simple desktop app for managing loyalty cards and customers points for restaurants and retailers in general.

NetAnimations

• Learning Object Repository of Computer Networking discipline of Computer Science course at State University of Maringá. Mobile app built with Ionic.

My Games App

• Simple app to register, keep track and share my platforms and games. Building with Ionic Framework.

Languages

Portuguese

Native or Bilingual

Enalish

Upper-intermediate

Spanish

Beginner

Interests

Software craftsmanship | Entrepreneurship |

Frameworks | Games | Web development |

Cloud computing | IoT | CI & CD |

Personal finances | Guitar solos